Guide to the Frédéric Louis Ritter Papers, approximately 1840-1891
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- Series IV. Published Music
  - 10 Irish Melodies [New York: Edward Schuberth & Co., 1875] (Folder 17.8)
    - — While gazing on the moon’s light
    - — The Shamrock
    - — The Minstrel Boy
  - Trio and Choruses for female voices (Folder 17.9)
    - — "To Earth May Winds are bringing" Pilgrimage of the Rose ®. Schumann, op. 112)
    - — The Spanish Tambourine-Girl (Schumann, op. 69)
    - — "Morn’s Gates again unclose" (M. Hauptmann)
    - — "Sprites of Air" Oberon C. M. von Weber)
    - — "Calm is the glassy" Idomenco (W. A. Mozart)
    - — Nightfall and Darkness (L. Giorigiani)
    - — The Tempest (Fabio Campana)
    - — "Low bending before you" Matrimonio Segreto (D. Cimarosa)
    - — The Stars (J. E. Leonhard)
  - 2 Sacred Songs [New York: Martens Brothers, 1872] (Folder 17.10)
    - — O Salutaris (2)
  - With Doubt and Trembling I Whisper’d in Her Ear (T.B. Aldrich) [Cincinnati: F.W. Rauch, 1859] (Folder 17.11)
  - Zehn Kinder-Lieder für eine Singstimme mit Begleitung des Pianoforte, op. 3 [Leipzig/New York: J. Schuberth & Co., 1867] II Heft (Folder 17.12)
    - — Wiegenlied/Cradle Song
    - — Vöglein und Englein/Birds and Angels
    - — Die drei Blümchen/The three Flowers
    - — Abendgebet/Evening prayer
    - — Gute Nacht/Good Night
  - Festival Cantata (IX Psalm.) for Solo voices, Chorus and Orchestra composed for the Celebration of the twenty fifth anniversary of Vassar College, op. 25 [New York: Edward Schuberth & Co.] (5) (Folder 11.1)
  - Fünf Lieder für Männerchor, op. 19. Leipzig: Fr. Kistner/New York: Edward Schuberth & Co., 1890; (2 copies) (Folder 11.2)
  - Gesang deutscher Auswanderer, für Männerchor [Cincinatti: Wm. Berger, 1855] (Folder 11.3)
  - The Rose of Jesse’s Race by M. Praetorius [Poughkeepsie, N.Y.: Chas. H. Hickok, 1882] (Folder 11.4)
  - Miscellaneous Published Music (Folder 11.5)
- Series V. Writings and Research Material
  - Reviews of Ritter's Work (Folder 14.9)
  - Advertisements for Ritter's Work (Folder 14.10)
  - Lecture Announcements (Folder 14.11)
  - Lecture Announcement (Folder 9.1)
  - "The History of the Hymntune" — Lecture and Notes (Folder 14.12)
  - A History of Music — Galley Proof (Folder 9.2)
  - A History of Music [?] — "Ancient Greek Scales" notebook (Folder 14.13)
  - A History of Music [?] — Notes (Folder 14.14)
  - Music in America — Notes (Folders 14.15 - 14.17)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Folders 14.18 - 14.19)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Folders 9.3-9.9)
  - Portfolio case for notes (Folders 9.10)
  - Clippings — Relating to Ritter (Folder 14.20)
  - Clippings — Richard Grant White articles (Folder 14.21)
  - Clippings — German (Folder 14.22)
  - Clippings — German (Folder 19.2)
  - Clippings — Miscellaneous (Folders 14.23)
  - Clippings — Miscellaneous (Folders 19.3-19.5)
  - Bibliographies (Folder 14.24)
  - Card File Bibliography (Boxes 15-16)
  - Article on Colonel George Ward Nichols [by Ritter?] (Folder 14.25)
- Series VI. Institutions, Clubs and Professional Organizations
  - Brighton Beach Music Hall, New York, June-Aug 1889; (12 items) (Folders 14.25 - 14.28)
  - [Central Park Garden?]— "Plan of Galleries and Promenade for Proposed Thomas Concert Garden and Hall (Folder 19.1)
  - Chickering Hall, 1879-1890, n.d. (Folder 14.29)
  - Church of the Holy Trinity, New York, 1869-1871 (Folder 14.30)
  - Church Music Association, 1869-1871 (Folder 14.31)
  - Music Teachers National Association (Folder 14.32)
  - New Orleans Philharmonic Society (Folder 14.33)
  - [New York City] Beethoven Jubilee, 1870 (Folder 14.34)
  - [New York City] May Festival, 1882 (Folder 14.35)
  - New York Philharmonic Society — Annual Reports, 1844-1884 (Folders 14.36 - 14.37)
  - New York Philharmonic Society — Programs, 1842-1891, n.d. (Folders 14.38 - 14.42)
  - New York Philharmonic Society — Miscellaneous, 1873-1880 (Folder 14.43)
  - Philharmonic Society of Brooklyn (Folder 14.44)
  - Poughkeepsie Vocal Union — Programs, 1881-1885 (Folder 14.45)
  - Poughkeepsie Vocal Union — Clippings, 1881-1885 (Folder 14.46)
  - Steinway Hall, NY, 1869-1871 (Folder 14.47)
  - United States Bureau of Education — Music in Public Schools, 1886 (Folder 14.48)
  - University of Trinity College — Exams (Folder 14.49)
  - Vassar College — F. L. Ritter Lecture Programs and Announcements, 1880-1890, n.d. (Folder 14.50)
  - Vassar College — Cecilia Society, 1870-1871, 1874 (Folder 14.51)
  - Vassar College — Soirée Musical, 1868-1891 (Folder 14.52)
  - Vassar College — School of Art announcements (Folder 14.53)
  - Vassar College — Music orders (Folder 14.54)
  - Vassar College — Miscellaneous Programs, 1869-1891 (Folder 14.55)
  - Miscellaneous Programs (Folder 14.56)
  - Miscellaneous Advertisements (Folder 14.57)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Materials (Folder 14.58)